But I do want to give you a quick bit background on asynchronous programming.
我要给你们简要介绍一下异步编程("asynchronous programming")的背景知识
So far, the programming that we've done has been synchronous.
目前为止，我们所做的编程都是同步的
And solidity is an example of a programming language, that synchronous,
solidity 就是一个同步编程语言的实例
Synchronous means it just goes one line after another.
同步的意思就是它只按照顺序一行接着一行往下运行
If our code looks like this, this is synchronous write,
如果我们的代码看起来是这样的，那这就是同步的，对吧？
our main function is the first thing that actually gets called.
我们的 main 函数首先被调用
Then we do console dot log, that variable equals five, and then console dot log. Again,
接着会运行 "console.log" 然后是 "variable = 5" 最后是再次运行 "console.log"
this is synchronous programming in JavaScript,
这就是 JavaScript 中的同步编程(synchronous programming)
all of our solidity is synchronously programmed.
我们的 solidity 则完全是同步编程的
There will be some exceptions to this when working with oracles.
使用预言机的时候会有一些例外
But for now, everything is synchronous.
但至少现在全都是同步的
JavaScript can be asynchronous,
JavaScript 可以是异步的
meaning that we can actually have code running at the same time.
这意味着我们可以让代码同时运行
A good example I like to use to understand the difference is with cooking.
有一个我很喜欢的例子可以用来区分二者的区别，就是类比烹饪
In synchronous programming, for cooking,
在同步编程中，用烹饪的例子来说
you might put popcorn in microwave, wait for popcorn to finish.
你可以把爆米花放到微波炉里，等待爆米花制作完成
And then, and then maybe you'll pour drinks for everyone.
接着，你可能会给大家倒点喝的
And now this is synchronous programming.
现在，这个过程就是一个同步编程
Now, it might be a little bit weird
但这个过程可能看起来有些奇怪，
for you just to put the popcorn in the microwave,
你先把爆米花放进微波炉
and then just stare at it, waiting for it to finish. And then pour the drinks,
然后就只是盯着它，等它做好，然后再去倒喝的
you typically can pour the drinks while your popcorn is in the microwave.
通常来说你可以一边倒喝的一边用微波炉加热爆米花
And this is where asynchronous programming comes in.
这就是要引入异步编程的地方了
If setting up for this movie night, we're asynchronous, what you would do is you'd put popcorn in the microwave.
如果把这个过程设置为一个异步的过程，你要做的就是先把爆米花放进微波炉
And while the popcorn is in the microwave, or drinks for everyone,
然后在爆米花还在微波炉里的时候，就去给大家倒喝的
and then you'd wait for popcorn finish,
最后你再等待爆米花制作完成
since there's nothing left for you to do,
因为你暂时也没什么其他事要做了
but it doesn't make sense for you to wait for the popcorn to finish to pour your drinks,
干等着爆米花做好再去倒喝的实在是毫无意义可言
you can just go ahead and pour the drinks right away and then wait for the popcorn to finish.
你完全可以先去倒喝的然后再等爆米花做好
So asynchronous programming is way for us to do stuff
所以异步编程就是这样一种执行方式
without waiting around for things to finish.
即不必干等着一件事做完再去做别的事
And this is really advantageous
这种方式是很有好处的
in JavaScript by default allows us to do this asynchronous programming,
JavaScript 默认就允许我们使用异步编程
however, sometimes we do want to wait for our popcorn to finish.
不过，有的时候我们确实就是想先等爆米花做好
For example, if instead of just pouring drinks,
比如说，如果这里不只是倒喝的
maybe the next thing instead of pouring drinks was placed salt on popcorn.
可能是给爆米花撒点盐而不是倒喝的
Of course, if we want to play salt on our popcorn,
当然了，如果我们要给爆米花撒盐
we do have to wait for the popcorn to get out of the microwave.
那我们确实要先等爆米花从微波炉里拿出来
So even though placing popcorn in the microwave has this wait time
所以即使把爆米花放进微波炉之后有这个等待时间
we need to be able to tell our code I want you to actually wait for it
我们也需要能够告诉我们的代码，我确实想先等着
or No, you're good. You can go on and do another task.
或是，不要干等着，你可以先去做其他任务
So that's kind of the difference here.
这就是二者的区别
And I'll leave some links in the GitHub repo associated with this course to understand this a little bit better
我会在课程关联的 GitHub 仓库中留下一些链接以便你更好地理解这一点
functions that have functions that come with this waiting period return something called a problem.
这个等待时间中函数可以返回一个被称为承诺("Promise")的东西
This, if put popcorn in the microwave was a function in JavaScript,
如果把“爆米花放进微波炉”看作是 JavaScript 的一个函数
it would be a promise based function.
那么它将是一个基于 "promise" 的函数
A promise can be either pending, fulfilled, or rejected.
一个 "promise" 可以是“挂起的”(Pending，也可以称为“进行中”)，“已成功”(Fulfilled)或是“已失败”(Rejected)
And this is how we know if our popcorn is done.
这样我们就能知道爆米花是否做好了。
If our popcorn was a method,
如果我们的爆米花是一种方法，呃...
putting popcorn in the microwave, were a function in JavaScript,
如果把爆米花放进微波炉是 JavaScript 中的一个函数
when we're waiting for the popcorn to finish, it's in a pending state.
当我们在等待爆米花制作完成的时候，它就是处于 "pending" 状态
When it's when the popcorn is finished, it would be fulfilled.
当爆米花已经做好的时候，它就是 "Fulfilled" 状态
And if we aborted halfway through, and we stopped waiting, it would be rejected.
如果我们中途放弃，不再继续等待了，它就是 "Rejected" 的
So putting the popcorn in the microwave returns a promise.
所以把爆米花放进微波炉会返回一个 "promise"
With this promise, we have to tell our code,
通过这个 "promise" 我们可以告诉代码
hey, we want you to wait for the popcorn to finish
嘿，我需要你先等爆米花做好
or you can go ahead and you can just keep doing stuff.
或者是，你可以继续先去做其他事
So let's put this all together with some JavaScript syntax here.
现在让我们用一些 JavaScript 语法来实现这些操作
Let's say again, we're going to be setting up this movie night.
回顾一下，我们现在要安排一下这个电影之夜
And we need to cook popcorn, pour drinks for everybody. And then we need to start a movie.
我们需要给大家制作爆米花，并倒一些喝的，接着就可以开始放电影了
So let's write some pseudocode
让我们来写一些伪代码("pseudocode")
to pretend what this code would look like if this was actually a function.
来假设这一切如果是一个函数
So we create some function called setup, Movie Night.
我们先创建一个函数叫作 "setupMovieNight"
And in here, we would say okay, what's the first thing we need to do?
这里，我们首先要做的是什么呢？
Okay, we need to cook popcorn.
OK，我们要先来制作爆米花
So let's say we have some cook popcorn function. So we'll say, okay, cook popcorn,
所以假设我们有一些制作爆米花的函数，我们要输入 "cookPopcorn()"
then the next thing we're gonna have to do is we're gonna have to pour drinks, or drink.
接下来要做的就是倒点喝的
So we'll call some pour drinks function.
所以我们要调用 "pourDrinks()" 函数
Now here's the thing, we only want to start the movie
现在，我们要想开始放电影
once our popcorn has been cooked. And once our drinks have been poured,
就要等爆米花先做好，并且喝的也要倒好
so if either one of these returned a promise,
所以如果其中的任何一个返回了 "promise"
so if either one of these returns a promise, like cook popcorn, for example,
如果其中任何一个返回了 "promise"，比如说 "cookPopcorn()"
we would need to tell our code here to actually wait for the popcorn to finish
我们就需要告诉这里的代码等待爆米花做好
because cook popcorn is going to be a function where we could say
因为 "cookPopcorn()" 是一个函数所以我们可以这样
let status equals cook popcorn.
"let status = cookPopcorn()"
And while the popcorn is being cooked, the status is going to be ending.
当爆米花正在制作的时，"status" 就是 "pending"
Once the popcorn gets cooked, it'll be fulfilled.
一旦爆米花做好了，它就会变成 "fulfilled"
If the popcorn breaks, the microwave explodes, the status would be rejected.
如果爆米花爆了微波炉也会爆炸，"status" 就变成了 "rejected"
But we don't want the status to be in a pending situation. Before we move on,
但我们不想还是 "pending" 状态的时候就继续前进
we only want to start our movie once these two functions have completed.
我们想的是当这两个函数都完成之后再开始我们的电影
And let's say both of these return these promises things.
让我们假设这两个函数返回的都是 "promise"
So we need to tell our code, hey, you have to wait.
所以我们需要告诉代码，嘿，你必须先等着
Or you have to wait for cook popcorn and for poor drinks to finish.
或者说你要先等 "cookPopcorn()" 和 "pourDrinks()" 都执行完
So what we can do
所以我们该怎么做？
now without getting too deep into the weeds on how all this works,
现在，在不深入研究这一切是怎么运作的前提下
one of the easiest things that we can do
我们能做的最简单的事情之一
and you'll see us use this syntax quite often
你能经常看到我们会使用这个语法
is we'll turn this function into an async function.
就是我们会把这个函数变成一个异步函数("async function")
When our functions are async, we get access to a keyword called await
当我们的函数是 "async" 的时候，我们可以访问一个名为 "await" 的关键字
the await keyword tells any promise based function
"await" 关键字告诉任何基于 "promise" 的函数
to wait for that promise to be fulfilled or rejected.
要等待 "promise" 变成 "fulfilled" 或 "rejected"
So we say okay, we want to await for our popcorn to cook.
所以我们说的就是，我们要先等待爆米花做好
And then we want to await to pour drinks. And then we can just go ahead and start the movie.
接着再等待喝的都倒好，然后我们就可以开始放电影了
And we only start the movie here once these two have been completed.
我们只有在这二者都完成之后才会开始放电影
And this is why throughout all of our code,
这就是为什么在我们所有的代码中
you'll see this await keyword used a lot.
你能看到这个 "await" 关键字会被大量使用
But it can only be used in async functions.
但它只能在异步函数中使用
So basically, whenever you see this await keyword just now
基本上，每当你看到这个 "await" 关键字时，你只需要知道
Ah, okay, the function that's being called is promise based.
啊，这个被调用的函数是基于 "promise" 的
And we don't want to move on to the next step until that function has completed.
我们不想在这个函数执行完之前就继续下一步
So that's a little bit more about promises and asynchronous programming.
所以这就是一些关于 "promise" 和异步编程的背景知识
Hopefully, that's clear. If not, like I said,
希望我已经讲清楚了，如果还没有的话，正如我之前说的
there's some links in the description to learn more about asynchronous programming.
描述中有一些链接可以学习更多关于异步编程的知识
The reason I wanted to go through this
我之所以会想要讲这些
is because most of the functions that we're going to be working with are going to be asynchronous.
是因为大多数我们要使用的函数都是异步的
For example, when we deploy a contract, what do we have to do?
举个例子，当我们部署合约的时候，我们要做什么？
Well, we have to wait for it to be deployed.
我们必须要先等待合约部署完成，对吧？
If we don't use synchronous programming,
如果我们不使用异步编程，
and we just leave our function main like this, what would happen is
让 main 函数就保持这样，那么会发生什么？
we would write some code like contract dot deploy,
我们写一些代码例如 "contract.deploy"
and we wouldn't wait for it to finish.
然后我们并不会等待它执行完
Obviously, if we don't wait for it to finish,
显然，如果我们不等它执行完
and we try to run some code on a contract that hasn't finished deploying it, it's not going to work.
并在它还没部署好的时候就尝试运行合约上的代码，那肯定是行不通的
So we want to do this, we want to have our main function be an async function,
所以我们要这么做，把我们的 main 函数写成一个 "async" 函数
so that we can we can wait for our contracts to deploy,
这样我们就可以等待我们的合约部署完成
we can wait for things to happen, we can wait for our popcorn to finish,
可以等待某些事已经发生，可以等待我们的爆米花制作完成
we can have the flexibility to tell our code
我们可以灵活地告诉我们的代码
to either wait for our popcorn to finish or continue on.
是等待爆米花完成还是继续下一步
So now that we have our main function as an async function,
所以现在我们的 main 函数就是一个异步函数了
we're going to add some code to our main function down here.
我们要在这里给 main 函数添加一些代码
And the code that's added here is some syntax for working with asynchronous functions.
这里添加的代码用的是一些处理异步函数的语法
And if this part is confusing, I'm just going to say for now, absolute, don't worry about this.
如果这部分让你感到困惑，那我现在就告诉你，绝对不用担心这个
If you want to try to understand that later. That's fine.
如果你之后想再尝试理解它，那很好
But for those who are following along,
不过对于跟着教程走的人来说
we're just going to add an add then catch air air
我们暂时就只是添加一个 "then" 和 "catch" 还有 "error"
you can follow along typing this yourself
你可以跟着自己把这些打出来
or you can just copy paste it into your code.
或是直接复制粘贴到你的代码中也行
Basically what this allows us to do
基本上我们做的就是
is we have our main function, that's an asynchronous function.
我们有一个 main 函数，它是一个异步函数
So when we call the main function, this is some other syntax for waiting for it to
当我们调用 main 函数的时候，这是一些其它语法
basically finish and then printing any errors it gets.
用于等待它完成并打印其中出的错误
And that's why we do this
这就是我们写这些东西的用处
but Again, if this big lump of code, if you're like what is going on with this big clump of code,
但是，如果这一大块代码，你现在就想搞清楚是怎么回事
honestly, for now, just copy paste it.
说真的，现在就先复制粘贴就行了
So great. We have our asynchronous function main, we have some code.
很好，我们有了异步函数 main，其中有一些代码
And then we have this lump of code, which basically just calls our main asynchronous function.
并且还有这一大块代码，基本上就是用来调用我们的异步 main 函数的
Okay, great. I'm gonna delete all this for now.
好了，现在我要把这些都删除掉
But you can still find that common in the GitHub repo associated with this course.
不过你仍然可以在课程关联的 GitHub 仓库中找到这些注释
Awesome. Okay, so now that we have our real basic setup,
太棒了，现在我们已经有了基本的配置
let's go ahead and start coding.
让我们继续编写代码
And if this set apart is confusing, and the async await stuff is confusing,
如果这部分你暂时搞不明白，或是 "async" 和 "await" 让你感到迷惑
don't worry too much about it.
不用过于担心这些东西
It'll make more sense as we progress.
随着我们的进展，它会变得更加清晰合理